（ﾛｰﾗ）
フンフン フフン♪
ンッ… ンッ… ハァ…
Archbishop!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
アークビショップ！
（ﾛｰﾗ）
な… なに？　アアッ！
Wh-What?
Is what's on this document correct?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
この報告書に書かれている項目は
本当なんですか？
Do you not realize that your words can change the world?
あなたのひと言は
世界を動かすこともあるんですから
何をいきなり―
What do you think you're doing?
レディーの浴室に
足を踏み入れたるのよ？　ステイル
You're walking in on a lady's bath, Stiyl!
聖職者にあるまじき無礼…
That's inexcusable for a holy worker—
Just answer me.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）いいから 答えろよ
（ﾛｰﾗ）アア…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
さあ
Now... Would you be so kind as to explain yourself?
詳細を説明してください　さあ！
Now!
（ﾛｰﾗ）
修道服が張り付きて
淫靡(いんび)なる肢体があらわになりて…
My clothes are clinging to me, leaving my voluptuous curves in plain view...
You can't!
私の肌は
何人(なんぴと)にも見せたるつもりは―
いけなし！
あちらを向きて ステイル
Avert your eyes, Stiyl!
なしにつきのだから
I mustn't allow others to behold my skin!
～♪
#18 Serial Number
Specimen Number
Why did that Archbishop have to get something so difficult to use?
（神裂(かんざき)）
アークビショップは―
なんで こんな複雑で面倒な物を
いただいてくるのでしょうか？
Sheesh...
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
まったく 洗濯なんぞ
川で やりゃいいじゃねえかよ
Just wash your clothes in the river.
A river's a little...
（神裂）
川は さすがに…
Apparently you push this button.
どうやら このボタンを
押すようなのでございますよ
How about we just wash clothes by hand?
素直に 手で洗いませんか？
Let's try just a little harder.
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
もう少しだけ頑張ってみましょう
The completely automated washing machine of our dreams stands right before our eyes!
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
夢の全自動洗濯機は
もう すぐそこなんですから
I thought you already finished doing the laundry for today.
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
今日の分の洗濯は
夕方 終わったんじゃないのか？
Right!
そうです　洗濯物がない以上…
Since there's nothing else to wash...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
いえ
No, we have more to wash.
（神裂･ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）うん？
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）洗濯物なら ここに
You don't have to take off your clothes just so we have something to wash!
（神裂）
わざわざ脱いでまで
増やす必要はないでしょう
And don't mimic her, you two!
（神裂）
そっちもマネしない！
それにしても 日本の浴衣は―
It seems quite simple to take off a Japanese yukata.
とても脱がしやすそうな構造を
しているのでございますね
アアッ！　ちょちょ… ちょっと！
H-H-Hey!
ああ… 神裂さんは下着を
はかない派なのでございますか？
Kanzaki-san, you don't wear any underwear?
That's how you wear a yukata!
浴衣とは そういうものなのです！
It's very quiet.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
本当に静かなのでございますよ
I can't believe we went through all that just for this...
（神裂）
これを見たいがためだけに…
（神裂）ハァ…
（ｼｪﾘｰ）おい 極東宗派
Hey, Far East girl.
今は抜け忍状態ですが 何か？
You should add on "former," but what is it?
The manual says to separate things that have fading colors.
説明書に “色落ちする物は―”
“分けてください”って
書いてあるけどよ
Is your dyed obi going to be fine?
あんたの染め物の帯は
大丈夫なのかしら？
C-Cancel... Where's the cancel button?
ちゅ… 中止… 中止のボタンは？
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
わあ…
You really aren't wearing panties.
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
本当に はいていないんですね
（美琴(みこと)）うわぁ！
（上条(かみじょう)）うん？
Gekota, Gekota, Gekota, Gekota!
（美琴）
ゲコ太ゲコ太 ゲコ太ゲコ太！
ハァ… やれやれ
Good grief...
（上条）
うん？　手続き終わったのか？
You finally done?
Er, what?
（上条）
…て あれ？
My God, Pyanko comes with Gekota?!
（美琴）ええっ？
（御坂(みさか)10032）うん？
（美琴）
ゲコ太と一緒に ピョン子まで？
Woohoo!
Meaning... you're Misaka's sister.
（上条）
…てことは
お前は御坂妹のほうか？
"Yes," replies MISAKA, adding her serial number 10032 for reference.
（御坂10032）
はい …と ミサカは念のため―
10032号とシリアルナンバーを
付け加えて肯定します
It's hard to tell without your goggles on.
（上条）
ゴーグル着けてなかったから
分からなかった
"Have you seen a MISAKA about this tall?" asks MISAKA, pointing just below her chest.
これくらいのミサカを
見かけなかったでしょうか？
…と ミサカは自分の胸の
ちょっと下辺りを指し示します
Can you guys change your height or something?
お前ら
サイズ変更とかできたのか？
"Judging from that question, you probably don't know," states MISAKA, losing confidence in your usefulness.
（御坂10032）
その反応からして
知らないようですね
…と ミサカは あなたの
役立たずっぷりに落胆します
ミサカは
ゴーグルを奪われてしまったのです
"MISAKA's goggles have been stolen."
"I need to get them back as soon as possible," hints MISAKA with pleading eyes.
早急に
回収しなければならないのですが
…と ミサカは暗に “手伝え”と
上目遣いで訴えてみます
W-Well, it is a bit hard to tell.
ま… まあ
ちょっと分かりにくいしな
You should keep your blazer off, or maybe—
とりあえず ブレザーでも
脱いどくとか　あっ…
Wait, why are you putting your hands on your skirt?
（上条）
…て
なんでスカートに手ぇかけてんだ？
No, wait!
なしなし！　脱ぐのは なし！
Don't strip!
（上条）
ハァ… あっ そうだ
Oh, I know.
If we get you some jewelry, it'd help.
何かアクセサリーとか着けてりゃ
見分けは つくだろう
Jewelry?
（御坂10032）アクセサリー？
（上条）例えば 指輪とか…
Maybe a ring.
A ring...
指輪…
"She has obtained information such as receiving good luck when putting an engagement ring on your left ring finger."
（御坂10039）
その際 好きな男性から
もらった指輪を―
左手薬指に
はめれば勝ち組との情報を―
極秘に入手していました
Hmm... Maybe not a ring.
（上条）
いや 指輪じゃダメだな
It doesn't stand out much.
（上条）目立たないし
（御坂10032）アア…
It'd need to be something that I could easily see...
もっと ぱっと見で分かる…
（留守電:ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
今 ミサカの下位個体と
追いかけっこしてるの
"I'm playing tag with MISAKA right now!" says MISAKA says MISAKA attempting to report her current situation.
…て ミサカはミサカは
現状報告してみたり
"I'm not coming home just yet, but I want you to make dinner for me,"
今すぐは帰れないけど
晩ご飯は作っておいてほしいかも
says MISAKA says MISAKA trying giving an order.
…て ミサカはミサカは
注文も出してみる
That damn brat!
It's because we left her alone.
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）
３人そろって部屋を空けたのが
マズかったじゃん
If she had only called one of us, we could've asked where she is.
（芳川(よしかわ)）
せめて 携帯にかけてくれたら
どこにいるのか聞き出せたのに
Let go, damn you!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ンンッ… 離せ こら
I said, let go!
離しやがれ！　あっ…
お～っと…
We'll leave Kikyou to watch over the house, then.
（黄泉川）
まあ 今度は
桔梗(ききょう)に留守を任せるじゃん
You're going to go look for her, aren't you?
（黄泉川）
捜しに行くんでしょう？　外に
あの子の後ろで
聞こえている音を解析できりゃ―
If we analyze the background sounds, we can narrow down her possible locations.
場所を絞れるじゃんよ
Well, just leave it to Yomikawa-oneesan.
まあ 黄泉川おねえさんに
任せておきなさいってね
（芳川）
それって職権乱用なんじゃない？
Isn't that abuse of your resources?
Searching for lost children is my job, too.
迷子の捜索も
お仕事のひとつじゃん
Come on, let's go.
さあ 行こうか
アア… 指輪
"A ring..."
MISAKA thinks about her left ring finger...
（御坂10032）
御坂は左手薬指の…
あのさ 気に入らないんだったら
返してこようか？
If you don't like it I can return it.
"Please don't take anything else from MISAKA," pleads MISAKA with a small voice.
（御坂10032）
これ以上
ミサカから何も奪わないでください
…と ミサカは小さな声で
切に語ってみます
ハァ… うん？
Animal donuts?
（上条）
“どうぶつドーナツ”？
Oh, they look pretty good.
（上条）
おお うまそう　いただきます！
Itadakimasu!
（御坂10032）チチチチ…
（上条）うん？
"Tweet, tweet, tweet..."
"These chicks are very well-behaved. They don't bite at all," says MISAKA, amazed.
かみつかないとは
利口なヒヨコたちです
…と ミサカは
感嘆の声を漏らします
They said that the product wasn't quite ready for sale, but they're still pretty good.
まだ実験段階の試作品って
言ってたけど 結構いけるな
"Even if it wasn't ready for sale..."
たとえ 実験品であっても…
"MISAKA thinks this chick's life was..."
ミサカは このヒヨコの命を…
（上条）
な… なにバチバチ言ってんだ？
What are you getting zappy for?
What the hell are you two doing?
（美琴）
ちょっと あんたたち
何やってんのよ？
M-Misaka...
（上条）み… 御坂
（御坂10032）ミ… ミサカは―
"MISAKA came here to take back the goggles that were stolen from her," says MISAKA—
奪われたゴーグルを取り戻すため
ここまで やって来たのです
と ミサカは… うん？
アア…
など いろいろありますが―
"Forget that, those frogs are amazing," says MISAKA, ending the topic.
もう
このカエルに夢中になっている
…と ミサカは話題を終わらせます
（美琴）…て こら
（御坂10032）あっ…
Hey!
Explain things to the end!
ちゃんと説明しなさいよ
Besides, you shouldn't be here...
大体
あんたは こんな所に いちゃ…
Hey, what are those? Lemme see.
なに それ？　ちょっと見せてよ
（御坂10032）
お姉様は そちらのカエルに
うつつを抜かしていればよいのです
"Onee-sama should just keep drooling over those frogs," denies MISAKA coldly.
…と ミサカは冷たく言い放ちます
別に いいじゃない 見るくらい
Come on, I'm just going to take a look.
（御坂10032）
そんなに欲しければ
ミサカと同じく―
"If you want to see them so badly, just have that person buy them like he did for me,"
その人に
買ってもらえばよいでしょう
states MISAKA, pointing at the person in question.
…と ミサカは当人を指し示します
（美琴）その人？
（上条）えっ？
That person?
（スパーク音）
ウワッ！
If I recall correctly, you were the guy who lost and had to listen to my every demand as punishment, right?
確か あんたは勝負に負けて―
罰ゲームで何でも言うこと聞くって
話になってたわよね
The punishment isn't over yet, so stop flirting!
（美琴）
人さまの罰ゲームの最中だってのに
（上条）アアッ！
（美琴）あっちこっちで―
いい顔しやがって！
Are you that much  into the "sister" thing?!
（美琴）
そんなに
妹って響きが好きか？　こら！
（御坂10032）
ところで お姉様は ここで何を？
"By the way, what are you doing here, Onee-sama?" asks MISAKA, beginning her interrogation.
…と
ミサカは情報収集を開始します
Well, we had a match during the Daihaseisai.
いやぁ…
大覇星(だいはせい)祭で ちょっと 勝負をね
And then I won, so I'm dragging him around.
そんで 私が勝ったから 罰ゲームで
あいつを引きずり回してるだけよ
So, uh...
え～っと… だから…
"In other words, you can't be honest to yourself?" asks MISAKA, analyzing the information.
つまり お姉様は
素直になれないのですか？
…と ミサカは情報を分析します
どう分析したら
そんな話になんのよ？
What kind of analysis would lead you to that?!
私に裏表なんかない
There's no ulterior motive to what I'm doing!
大体 こんなヤツに素直になって
どうしろっていうのよ？
Besides, what's the point of being honest with him?!
"I see."
（御坂10032）
そうですか　では―
"Then MISAKA will try walking down a different path from the original."
ミサカはオリジナルとは
違う道を歩んでみます
（上条･美琴）
ウワッ！
（御坂10032）
ちらりと―
"Ta-da," says MISAKA as she shows off the piece of jewelry he bought for her.
ミサカは買っていただいた
アクセサリーを―
さりげなく
オリジナルに見せつけてみます
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカも反対側から抱きついてみる
"MISAKA tries hugging him from the other side, too!" says MISAKA says MISAKA joining in on the fun!
…て ミサカはミサカは
面白そうなことに―
交ぜてもらってみたり
"MISAKA"? Wait...
（上条）
“ミサカ”って まさか 妹の妹？
You mean she's a sister of the sister?!
Serial number 20001.
（御坂10032）
シリアルナンバー20001号
"You sure have guts, showing up in front of MISAKA," says MISAKA as she subtly switches to full-power mode.
ミサカの前にノコノコ現れるとは
いい度胸ですね
…と ミサカは
にわかに本気モードに移行します
"MISAKA got bored of that game already,"
ミサカは もう
そのゲームには飽きてしまったのだ
says MISAKA says MISAKA while going to look for new sources of entertainment!
…て ミサカはミサカは
次なるエンターテインメントの―
発掘に出かけてみたり
"I won't let you escape this time," says MISAKA as she pulls a rifle from her bag.
逃がすとお思いですか？
…と ミサカは
カバンからライフルを取り出します
"That sure is a crappy ‘full-power mode' you got there!" says MISAKA says MISAKA mocking her enemy!
その程度で本気とは
片腹痛いって―
ミサカはミサカは
小バカにしてみたり
"I haven't gone all-out just yet," says MISAKA as she makes the final transformation to MISAKA full-booster mode.
まだまだ本番は これからです
…と ミサカは―
ミサカフルブーストへと
最終展開します
What?
（上条）
何だ？
The underground shopping center?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
地下街だ？
（黄泉川）
留守電に
残ってたメッセージから―
There were inaudible constant-frequency sound waves for tracing that we extracted out of the message, right?
逆探知用の可聴域外低周波が
検出されたじゃん
They came from Area U, which is the underground shopping center.
（黄泉川）
…で そいつがエリアＵ
すなわち 地下街用だったってわけ
And you want me to go there?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
…で 俺に そこへ向かえってのか？
For now.
（黄泉川）
ひとまずはね
But we don't really know if that hyperactive kid is still there or not.
もっとも
あのすばしっこいのが―
今も同じ所にいるのかは
分からないけど
Hey, Accelerator.
（黄泉川）ねえ アクセラレータ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）何だ？
What?
（黄泉川）
人に好意を向けることが
そんなに怖い？
Is showing goodwill towards others really that scary?
…んだと？
The hell?
You seem to have accepted Last Order's goodwill; you're afraid to reciprocate her.
君はラストオーダーからの好意を
受け入れてるみたいだけど―
自分から あの子へ
好意を向けることは拒んでいる
Are you afraid of screwing up and being unable to fix it?
（黄泉川）
裏目に出て 取り返しが
つかなくなることが怖いから
説教か？
Are you lecturing me?
（黄泉川）
まあ 私ごときに君の闇を
理解できるとは思わないけど
Well, I suppose that I can't really understand your darkness.
Especially because of the place you were in long ago.
君が昔いた場所が場所だけにね
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
“特力研”だろう
“特例能力者多重調整技術研究所”
The Special Ability Institute?
"Special Ability Holders Multiple Alteration Technologies Research Institute."
I was kept there until I was nine.
俺は９歳まで
あそこに放り込まれてた
It was a facility used for disposing live people.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
あそこは生きた人間を
処分するための掃きだめさ
You've probably at least heard rumors.
話ぐれえ聞いたことはあんだろう？
（黄泉川）
あそこを制圧 解体したのは
私の部隊だったからね
My unit was responsible for dismantling it.
Oh, boy. Thanks.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）そりゃ どうも
（黄泉川）私も見たよ
I've seen them.
Lying around on the other side of a heavy door.
重たい扉の向こうに
横たわっている“それ”を
I was nothing but a monster, even in that institute.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
俺は その特力研さえ持て余す
怪物だったんだ
芳川から聞いてんだろう？
俺が実験で何をしてきたか
I'm sure you've heard of it from Yoshikawa.
About what I did in those experiments.
There's no way I could show goodwill to anyone.
好意を向けるなんざ
不可能なんだよ
Yet, you're sick of yourself, aren't you?
それでも君は そんな自分を
嫌悪している　違う？
これは私が自分に
課しているルールなんだけど―
This is a rule I made for myself:
I will never point a weapon at a child.
私は子供に対して武器を向けない
たとえ 能力者が相手でもね
どうしてか分かる？
Even if they're an esper.
Do you know why?
（黄泉川）
そういうことよ
That's exactly it.
It's probably nothing compared to what you have to face.
確かに 君とは比べものに
ならないかもしれないけど
But the fact that we're heavily indebted to others is the same.
負債を抱えていることに
変わりはない
So no matter how painful it is, there's no choice but to pay back as much as possible.
だったら どんなにブザマでも
払い続けるしかないじゃんよ
And unlike me, you have strength.
それに 君には
私と違って力がある
手は いくらでもあるじゃんよ
There are many doors that are open to you.
What if I used my strength to stop the experiment?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
もしも
この力で実験を止めていれば…
What if I helped those Sisters who walked to their death?
もしも
死の道へ突き進む あいつらを―
押さえつけることができていれば…
What if it's not too late?
もしも
今からでも遅くないのなら…
What if...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
もしも…
くっだらねえ
Retarded.
That feeling you have will eventually pay back your debt.
（黄泉川）
そのくだらないものの
積み重ねが―
負債を返していくじゃんよ
Bullshit.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
くそったれが
（ノイズ）
（男性）何だ？ ありゃ
（警備員(アンチスキル)Ａ）
これか 通報にあったのは
Is this the one we were alerted about?
（警備員Ｂ）
よくできた立体映像だな
That's an impressive holographic projection.
（警備員Ａ）
まったく
手の込んだ いたずら しやがって
Seriously, man.
What a well-done prank.
本部へ連絡して 該当する能力者を
洗い出してもらうか
Let's contact HQ and get a list of the espers who might be involved.
（上条）
…たく　何だったんだ？　一体
Man, I don't get it anymore.
（美琴）あのクソバカ！
（殴る音）
You stupid idiot!
人の交わした約束を
何だと思ってんのよ！
Is that how important a promise is to you?!
（男性）わあ すごい！
（美琴）ハァハァ…
I don't get it.
分からん　分からんが 不幸だ
I don't get it, but...
Such misfortune.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
なにを疲労感に
肩を落としているの？
"Why are you dropping your shoulders so wearily?" asks MISAKA asks MISAKA...
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）て ミサカはミサカは
（上条）うん？
アア… ウワッ！
while clinging to your back as a therapeutic mascot!
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
癒やし系マスコットとして
あなたの背中に張り付いてみたり
Hey!
お前 さっきのミニ御坂？
You're that… mini-Misaka?
Touma...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻(とうま)…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
What the heck's this?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
何なんだ？　こりゃ
So, I was looking for Touma,
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
…でね
私は当麻を捜してたんだけど―
途中で おなかが減っちゃって
それでね
but then I got so hungry so—
食うか しゃべるか どっちかにしろ
Don't talk with your mouth full.
つうか 俺に
何か言うことがあるんじゃねえのか
And don't you have anything to say to me?
あ～ん…
うん ありがとうね
Yeah!
Thanks!
That's it?
ひと言かよ
My name's Index!
えっとね 私の名前は
インデックスっていうんだよ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
汚ねえツラで自己紹介か
That sure is one messy face to introduce yourself with.
Have you seen a brat like this anywhere?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
お前
こういうガキ 見たことあるか？
Nope.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ないよ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）即答かよ
That was fast.
I never forget a face once I've seen it.
私は
一度見た人の顔は忘れないから
Thank you so much though!
アア… でも 良かった
Now I can search for Touma without worrying about food!
これで おなかのことを気にせず
当麻を捜しに行けるし
おなかが
いっぱいになっちゃったから―
Well, now that I'm full,
当麻を捜す理由も
薄くなっちゃった気もするけど
there's probably less reason to search for him anyway...
Is that so?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ああ そうかい
俺は手伝わねえぞ　よそ当たれ
Too bad I won't be helping you.
Go bug someone else.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
忙しいの？
Are you busy?
Yeah. Very busy, unfortunately.
ああ あいにくと大忙しだ
So, you're basically like... a sort of "host computer" for the other Sisters?
（上条）
つまり お前は
妹たちを束ねてる―
ホストコンピューターみたいな
もんなのか？
"Well, more like a console rather than a host," says MISAKA says MISAKA trying to clarify.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ホストというより
コンソールに近いかもって―
ミサカはミサカは訂正してみたり
"There's no ‘core' to the MISAKA network, so there's no need for one particular individual to act as a hub,"
ミサカの中心点は どこにもなくて
ネットワークの中で特定の個体が
核として存在することには―
あんまり意味がないのって―
says MISAKA says MISAKA as she attempts to proudly puff her chest out while lecturing.
ミサカはミサカは
偉そうに胸を張って講釈してみる
"Actually, I came here to thank you for your help during that experiment,"
あのね ミサカは実験のときに―
あなたに助けてもらったから
お礼を言いに来たの
says MISAKA says MISAKA while putting on "The Grateful Crane" pose.
…て ミサカはミサカは
鶴の恩返し的展開を提示してみたり
So why are you really here?
（上条）…で 本音は何なんだよ？
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）アア…
"You didn't believe me!"
一瞬たりとも信用してないし！
says MISAKA says MISAKA while stomping the ground in anger, and waving her hands around because she can't stop!
…て ミサカはミサカは
じだんだを踏んでみたり！
勢い余って
両手を振り回してみたり！
悪い悪い 悪かった
Sorry, sorry! My bad!
Look, I'll buy you some popcorn!
（上条）
ほら あれ買ってやるから
許してくれ なっ？
So forgive me, okay?
お… 女の子の繊細な心を―
"You think you can sway a girl's delicate feelings with food?" says MISAKA says MISAKA frowning in disappointment.
食べ物ごときで
誘導できると思ってるの？
…て
ミサカはミサカは憮然(ぶぜん)としてみる
You see, Touma's always leaving me behind and running off somewhere.
でね 当麻は いっつも
私を置いてけぼりにして―
どっかに行っちゃうんだよ
あれは もう放浪癖の一種なのかも
I think he's some sort of closet nomad...
He's always finding himself suddenly caught up traveling somewhere.
気がついたら
旅に出ている人なんだよ
By the way, what are you doing here?
ところで
あなたは ここで何してるの？
Looking for someone.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）人捜しだ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）さっきの携帯の子？
The girl in that picture?
Yeah, so what?
だったら 何だよ？
Oh yeah, I haven't repaid you for the meal yet.
そういえば
まだお礼をしていなかったね
Whatever, just shut up and go home, you damn brat.
いいから 黙って帰れ クソガキ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
まだお礼をしていなかったね
I haven't repaid you for the meal yet.
俺の言ったこと
スルーしてんじゃねえぞ こら！
Don't just ignore what I say!
That girl from the picture, right?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
さっきの子なんだよね？
How about I help you look for her until I find Touma?
当麻が見つかるまで
一緒に捜してあげてもいいよ
Okay?
くそったれが！
Little shithead.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
プハ～ッ！
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）あのね
（上条）うん？
"You know..."
"MISAKA ran off with this!" says MISAKA says MISAKA while boasting her loot.
ミサカは これをかっ払ってきたの
…て ミサカはミサカは
戦利品を自慢してみたり
何だ？　人心地つくや
今度は いきなり山賊宣言かよ
You relax a little and then announce you're a bandit?
Wait, aren't those the goggles MISAKA's sister was looking for?
…て そのゴーグル
御坂妹が捜してたヤツか
"This wasn't made for MISAKA though, so I can't wear it right..."
でも これはミサカのために
作られた物じゃないから―
うまく装着できないの
…て ミサカはミサカは
ちょっと しょんぼりしてみる
says MISAKA says MISAKA while seeming a bit downcast.
Can't you just adjust the length of the headband?
つうか バンドの長さを―
調整すりゃいいんじゃねえの？
う… うん？　あれ？
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）ウワッ！
（上条）アア…
A-Are you okay?
（上条）
だ… 大丈夫か？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
う～ん…
どっかで見たことあるような…
I kind of feel like I've seen her before...
でも ちょっと小さすぎるような…
But I feel like she's too small...
Yeah, I guess I don't know her after all.
うん やっぱり 見覚えないんだよ
Then give it back, you useless little brat!
だったら返せ
この役立たずのクソガキが
There, done!
（上条）
よし 完成
おお！　これなら
ミサカにもバッチリなのって―
"This fits MISAKA perfectly now!" says MISAKA says MISAKA trying to express her gratitude.
ミサカはミサカは感激してみたり
"But the cost of this achievement was definitely not small,"
でも 払った代償は
決して小さくなかったかも
says MISAKA says MISAKA remembering but tries spinning around in happiness anyway.
…て ミサカはミサカは
思い出しながら―
とりあえず 全身で
喜びを表してみる！　フフフフッ…
は～いはい
Yeah, sure.
"Um... MISAKA has to go back soon," says MISAKA says MISAKA while regretfully informing you.
あのね ミサカは
そろそろ帰らないといけないの
…て ミサカはミサカは
残念なお知らせをしてみたり
Ah, yeah. I guess it's time.
ああ… 時間も時間だからな
"I actually wanted to stay with you longer," says MISAKA says MISAKA sadly.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
本当は もっと
一緒にいたかったんだけどって―
ミサカはミサカは…
しょんぼりしてみたり
ここで会ったのは
たまたまだったけど―
"We may have met here by accident, but I really did want to thank you,"
お礼をしたかったって気持ちは
本当だし
says MISAKA says MISAKA speaking from her heart.
…て ミサカはミサカは
心中を吐露してみる
"But he's probably getting worried..."
でも あの人は心配すると思うんだ
"He"?
“あの人”？
"If I'm too late, he might come looking for me,"
あんまり遅いと ミサカのことを
捜しに来るかもしれないし
"and I don't want to cause trouble for him," says MISAKA says MISAKA smiling.
ミサカも迷惑とかは
かけたくないから
…て ミサカはミサカは
笑いながら言ってみる
（上条）
ふ～ん…
いいヤツそうじゃないか そいつ
He sounds like a good guy.
"He's weak..."
弱いんだよ
"He's been hurt so much that not only was he unable to protect what he held in his hands"
あの人は いっぱい傷ついて
手の中のものを
守れなかったばかりか―
"but he even wore them out in the process."
それを救っていた両手も
ボロボロになっちゃってるの
"That's why I don't want to strain him anymore."
だから
これ以上は負担をかけたくないし
"This time MISAKA will be the one who protects him!" says MISAKA says MISAKA trying an honest declaration.
今度は ミサカが守ってあげるんだ
…て
ミサカはミサカは打ち明けてみる
（上条）
そっか
I see.
うん？　あっ… 当麻だ！
Ah, it's Touma!
The guy you're looking for?
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）お前が捜してヤツか？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん
Yeah!
Ah.
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
チッ…　行けよ
Go.
えっ？
でも あなたの知り合いのほうは？
But what about you?
Don't worry, I just found her.
心配すんな　こっちも今 見つけた
I'm off, then.
じゃ 行くね ありがとう
Thank you!
ラストオーダー！
Last Order!
Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻！
（上条）フフッ…
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ハァハァ… ただいま！
"I'm back!" says MISAKA says MISAKA doing her usual greeting—
…て
ミサカはミサカは定番の挨拶を…
（殴る音）
いてっ！
Ow!
…て なんで無言で
連続チョップするの？
"Why are you hitting me and not saying anything?"
…て ミサカはミサカは
頭を押さえてウソ泣きしてみる
asks MISAKA asks MISAKA covering her head and trying to pretend she's crying.
What were you doing all this time?
つうか お前は
今さっきまで何してたわけ？
あっ… 遊んでもらってたの
"Having fun!" says MISAKA says MISAKA trying to answer honestly.
…て ミサカはミサカは
正直に答えてみたり
ハァ… ああ？
Hey, Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 当麻 やっと見つけたんだよ
I finally found you!
Why are you here?
（上条）
お前 なんで こんな所に？
Well, that person there saved me when I was in danger!
あのね あのね 危ないところを
あの人に助けてもらったんだよ
Which person?
（上条）
…て どの人だ？
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）アクセラレータ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）うん？
Accelerator!
If you don't hurry, I'll leave you behind!
早く来ないと置いてっちゃうよ
チッ… うるせえな クソガキが
Such a noisy little brat.
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
あいつの前に現れた白衣の男
A man in a lab coat appears before him.
The streets begin to take on a dangerous vibe.
街は一気に
危険な かおりに満ちる
And one of God's Right Seat...
そして 神の右席 そのひとりまで
次回 「木原数多(けんきゅうしゃ)」
Next time: "Researcher."
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる